所以我们在讨论如何避免虫子。
So we're talking about how to avoid bugs.
我们的第一道防线是
And our first defense is to make them
根据我们的程序设计是不可能的
impossible by the design of our program
或者是编程语言和运行时系统的设计
or the design of the programming language and runtime system
写在里面的。
that it's written in.
静态检查是我们已经讨论过的一种方法
Static checking is one way that we've actually already talked
关于。
about.
事实上，你会在一读的时候记得的。
You'll remember this back in the first reading, in fact.
我们讨论了静态检查和动态检查。
We talked about static checking and dynamic checking.
例如，Java防止您意外地
Java prevents you, for instance, from accidentally passing
函数的整数值，需要严格的。
an integer value to a function and expects a strict.
它甚至不会让你的代码编译，
It won't even let your code compile,
它甚至不让你运行它。
it won't even let you run it.
所以静态检查消除了很多错误
So static checking eliminates a lot of bugs
通过在编译时很早地捕获它们。
by catching them very early at compile time.
我们还看到了一些动态检查的例子
We also saw some examples of dynamic checking
在之前的阅读中。
in that earlier reading.
例如，Java会产生数组溢出错误
For example, Java makes array overflow bugs
通过动态捕捉它们是可能的。
possible by catching them dynamically.
如果试图使用数组边界之外的索引
If you try to use an index outside the bounds of an array
列表中，Java将在运行时自动生成错误。
list, Java will automatically produce an error at runtime.
像C和C++这样的老图书馆只是默默地允许这些类型
Older libraries like C and C++ just silently allow those kinds
错误的访问，这导致一种非常常见的安全性
of bad accesses, which leads to a very common kind of security
称为缓冲区溢出的漏洞。
vulnerability called a buffer overflow.
不变性是另一个设计原则。
Immutability is another design principle.
我们会经常讨论这个问题，
We're going to talk about this a lot,
但这对防止虫子真的很好。
but it's really great for preventing bugs.
因此，不可变类型是其值永远不能更改的类型
So an immutable type is the type whose values can never change
一旦它们被创造出来。
once they've been created.
字符串是不可变类型的一个很好的例子。
String is a good example of an immutable type.
没有可以调用的方法
There are no methods you can call
在将更改字符序列的字符串上
on string that will change the sequence of characters
它所代表的。
that it represents.
你可以把绳子传来传去
You can pass the string around and share it
与你的程序的其他部分没有任何恐惧
with other parts of your program without any fear
其他部分可以修改它。
that those other parts will be able to modify it.
这样就避免了一整类常见的错误。
And that avoids an entire class of common bugs.
Java实际上也给了我们不可变的引用。
Java actually also gives us immutable references.
这是您声明的变量
That is variables that you declare
使用关键字final，可以指定一次
with the keyword final, which can be assigned once
但从未被重新分配。
but never reassigned.
尽可能多地使用final是个好习惯。
It's good practice to use final as much as you can.
因为就像变量的类型一样，
Because like the type of the variable,
就像叫它实习生字符串，那个声明
like calling it intern string, that declaration
这是最后的重要文件。
that it's final is important documentation.
所以考虑这个例子。
So consider this example.
我们有一个变量值，它的类型是字符数组。
We've got a variable values, whose type is Character array.
这被宣布为最终结果
And that is declared final, which
意味着values变量不能
means that the values variable can't ever
指向除第一个分配给它的对象以外的任何对象。
point to anything other than what its first assigned to.
它的第一个分配给这个字符数组。
And its first assigned to this character array.
这是文件变量。
So this is files variable.
它被宣布为决赛，但这真的是一成不变的。
It's declared final, but this is really unchanging.
所以问题是，这两个陈述中的哪一个，
So the question is, which of these two statements,
这个给一个新的字符数组赋值，
this one that assigns values to a new character array,
一个完全不同的物体，或者这个
a completely different object, or this one that
改变字符数组的一个元素
mutates one element of the character array
价值指向什么？
that value points to?
哪一个，或者两者都有，或者两者都没有
Which of these, or both, or neither
Java编译器允许吗？
are allowed by the Java compiler?
你将在下一个练习中找到答案。
You'll find the answers in the next exercise.
但是你应该从那次练习中学到什么
But what you should learn from that exercise
你真的要小心决赛
is you have to be careful about what final actually
意思是在Java中。
means in Java.
它只会使这个变量不可变，不一定
It only makes this variable immutable, not necessarily
变量指向的对象。
the object that the variable points to.